# ANDREW PUCCI

**USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER** 

## **VALUES**

- Always be learning
- Be honest
- · Embrace diversity
- · Have flexibility
- Make a difference
- Provide transparency
- · Seek autonomy
- Strive for balance

A user experience designer who has the breadth of a UX generalist, but has a special interest in interaction design and user research. Has worked across multiple industries and in companies as small as an early-stage startup to a Fortune 500 enterprise. Brings experience in software development and organization design to build collaboration across teams.

## PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

## **SOCIETY OF GROWNUPS**

**BROOKLINE. MA** 

A startup focused on fostering financial literacy through education and individualized advice.

### USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER 2014-2016

Reporting to CEO, created a singular customer experience both digitally and physically. Also, improved internal process during business growth.

- Produced internal and external facing websites, creating a singular customer experience both digitally and physically.
- Designed (with IDEO) a Webby Award-winning website that enabled users to build a plan to accomplish their financial goals.
- Performed usability studies with our customer service team, producing mockups which, once implemented, improved usability of internal systems.
- Created wireframes for and developed (in HTML/CSS) a sweepstakes page for a marketing promotion, resulting in increased brand awareness through social platforms.
- Designed and participated in interviewing and onboarding processes, which ensured new employees had access to tools and information resulting in accelerated productivity.
- Constructed a three part organization design that facilitated better communication and reduced work redundancy across the company.
- Implemented programs to increase recognition of efforts throughout the company which resulted in higher employee satisfaction on engagement survey.

## **TELERIK**

HUDSON, OH

Services division of a Bulgaria-based software company that creates tools for software developers.

## USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER 2012-2014

Improved usability of software products across both Telerik and third-party client systems.

- Developed wireframes and prototypes for a software analytics application, adding a new offering to a larger suite of products.
- Recruited for and ran usability studies for software development and debugging tools, leading to design improvements that reduced the amount of support requests for these products.
- Ran surveys and usability studies, and created wireframes for websites across the Telerik portfolio, increasing their usability and marketability.









# ANDREW PUCCI

**USER EXPERIENCE DESIGNER** 

## SKILLS

- Wireframes
- · Prototypes (All Fidelities)
- · Competitive Analysis
- · Usability Studies
- Storyboards
- Surveys
- · Participant Recruitment
- Blueprints / Sitemaps
- HTML/CSS/JavaScript
- Agile Methodology
- · Organization Design

# **TOOLS**

- Balsamiq
- Adobe Illustrator
- · Sketch
- InVision
- Camtasia
- · Adobe Photoshop
- · AxureRP
- Microsoft Visio
- · Keynote / Powerpoint
- Git/Github

## **FIRSTENERGY**

AKRON, OH

A Fortune 500 electric utility serving customers throughout Ohio, Pennsylvania, and New Jersey.

#### DATA MODELER 2008-2012

Worked with business clients to gain an understanding of their operations, helping design reporting systems that will answer their most important business questions.

Interviewed business clients to produce deep insight into their business processes and needs. This knowledge was then built into data models and wireframes for reporting interfaces which gave clients the ability to make data-driven decisions.

## WEB DEVELOPER 2007-2008

Developed tools for users of our internal and external websites.

- Developed web applications in J2EE, HTML, and CSS, notably, increasing stability of "contact us" form.
- Administered a web content management system, enabling business users to easily update content on customer-facing website.

## **EDUCATION**

MASTER OF SCIENCE, INFORMATION ARCHITECTURE AND KNOWLEDGE MANAGEMENT (UXD) KENT STATE UNIVERSITY, KENT, OH

BACHELOR OF SCIENCE, SOFTWARE ENGINEERING CLARKSON UNIVERSITY, POTSDAM, NY

## **VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE**

#### BOARD OF DIRECTORS, PRESIDENT OF THE BOARD

UXPA (USER EXPERIENCE PROFESSIONALS ASSOCIATION) CLEVELAND

#### **CHAPTER CHAIR**

NORASIST (NORTHERN OHIO CHAPTER OF ASIS&T, ASSOCIATION FOR INFORMATION SCIENCE AND TECHNOLOGY)

#### BOARD OF DIRECTORS, PRESIDENT OF THE BOARD

YOUNG PROFESSIONALS OF AKRON

#### **VOLUNTEER (PEER REVIEWER)**

**UXPA BOSTON CONFERENCE** 

#### **VOLUNTEER (PEER REVIEWER)**

INFORMATION ARCHITECTURE (IA) SUMMIT

#### **VOLUNTEER**

**BOSTON TECHJAM** 

### **EMERGING LEADER**

DOWNTOWN AKRON PARTNERSHIP